// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the name of the safety sign as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img1",
    answer: "Information Sign",
    options: [
      "Warn Sign",
      "Mandatory Sign",
      "Information Sign",
      "Danger Sign"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is smothering in extinguishing of fire?",
    answer: "Isolating the fire from the supply of oxygen",
    options: [
      "Adding the fuel element to the fire",
      "Removing the fuel element from the fire",
      "Using of water to lower the temperature", 
      "Isolating the fire from the supply of oxygen"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which step of the 5s-concept refers Standardization?",
    
    answer: "Step-4",
    options: [
      "Step-1",
      "Step-2",
      "Step-3",
      "Step-4"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which pliers is used for making the wire hooks and loops?",
    answer: "Round nose pliers",
    options: [
      "Flat nose pliers",
      "Long nose pliers",
      "Round nose pliers",
      "Diagonal cutting pliers"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What is the use of the pincer?",
    answer: "Extracting the pin nails from the wood",
    options: [
      "Twisting the flexible wires",
      "Cutting larger diameter of wires",
      "Extracting the pin nails from the wood",
      "Holding small objects, where finger cannot reach"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which plier is used for making wire hooks and loops?",
    answer: "Yellow",
    options: [
      "Blue",
      "White",
      "Yellow",
      "Green"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What is the use of pincer? ",
    answer: "Incineration",
    options: [
      "Landfill",
      "Composting",
      "Incineration",
      "Water compaction"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which disposal method of waste save lot of energy?",
   
    answer: "Recycling",
    options: [
      "Land fill",
      "Recycling",
      "Incineration",
      "Composting"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Diagonal cutting pliers",
    immg:"img9",
    options: [
      "Nose pliers",
      "Crimping tool",
      "Combination plier",
      "Diagonal cutting pliers"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the name of the file as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img10",
    answer: "Rasp cut file",
    options: [
      "Curved cut file",
      "Single cut file ",
      "Double cut file",
      "Rasp cut file"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 11,
    question: "What is the name of the drill bit as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img11",
    answer: "Taper shank bit",
    options: [
      "Flat drill bit",
      "Taper shank bit",
      "countersink bit",
      "straight shank bit"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which file is used for sharpening the blunt teeth of a tenon saw?",
    
    answer: "Triangular file",
    options: [
      "square file",
      "round file",
      "Triangular file",
      "half round file"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 13,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked ‘X’ as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img13",
    answer: "Heel",
    options: [
      "Edge",
      "Tang",
      "Heel",
      "point"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 14,
    question: "What is the name of the hammer as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "claw hammer",
     immg:"img14",
    options: [
      "claw hammer",
      "Ball pein hammer",
      "Cross pein hammer",
      "Straight pein hammer"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 15,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
     immg:"img15",
    answer: "Ball pein hammer",
    options: [
      "Claw hammer",
      "Tack hammer",
      "cross pein hammer",
     "Ball pein hammer"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which is the physical hazard?",
    
    answer: "Vibration",
    options: [
      "smoking",
      "Vibration",
      "corrosive",
      "bacteria"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which type of fire extinguisher is used for fire on electrical equipment?",
    
    answer: "Halon type",
    options: [
      "Halon type",
      "Foam type",
      "Gas cartridge water type",
      "Stored pressure water type"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the name of the tool as shown in the figure?",
      immg:"img18",
    answer:"pincer",
    options: [
      "wire stripper",
      "slide cutter",
      "pincer",
      "gimlet"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which is the correct sequence of operation to be performed while using the fire extinguisher?",
    
    answer:"Pull, Aim, Squeeze, Sweep",
    options: [
      "Pull, Aim, Squeeze, Sweep",
      "Pull, Aim, Sweep, Squeeze",
      "Push, Arrange, Squeeze, Sweep",
      "Push, Arrange, Sweep, Sequence"
    ]
  },
        {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) is used for the protection from fumes?",
   
    answer:"Respirator",
    options: [
      "Apron",
      "Goggles",
      "Ear muff",
      "Respirator"
    ]
  },  
    
             {
    numb: 21,
    question: "What is starving in extinguishing of fire?",
    
    answer:"Removing fuel element from the fire",
    options: [
      "Adding fue to the fire",
      "Using water to cool the fire ",
      "Removing fuel element from the fire",
      "Preventing oxygen supply to the fire"
    ]
  },
                 
        {
    numb: 22,
    question: "Which artificial respiration method is to be performed to the victim with injuries on the chest and belly?",
    
    answer:"Mouth to mouth method",
    options: [
      "Schafers method",
      "Mouth to mouth method",
      "Holger Nelson back pressure method",
      "Nelson arm lift back pressure method"
    ]
  },  
     {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Which type of occupational health hazard is cause for infection due to bacteria?",
    
    answer:"Biological hazard",
    options: [
      "Electrical Hazard",
      "Physiological hazard",
      "Biological hazard",
      "Pschological hazard"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which is the golden hour for the victim injured on head with risk of dying?",
    
    answer: "First 30 minutes",
    options: [
      "First 15 minutes",
      "First 30 minutes",
      "First 45 minutes",
     "First 60 minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "Which condition of the victim is referred as COMA stage?",
    
    answer: "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls",
    options: [
      "Un consscious but can respond to calls",
      "Consicous but cannot resopnd to call",
      "Breathing and respond to call",
     "Lie totally senseless and do not respond to calls"
    ]
  },        
               {
    numb: 26,
    question: "Which criteria must be satisfied for the quality of PPE s?",
    
    answer:"It should with stand the hazards",
    options: [
      "It should with stand the hazards",
      "It cannot be used for long period",
      "made by non standard material",
      "low cost"
    ]
  }, 
     {
    numb: 27,
    question: "What is the possible range to measure the size of the wire in a Standard Wire Gauge(SWG)?",
    
    answer: "0-36",
    options: [
      "0-44",
      "0-42",
      "0-38",
     "0-36"
    ]
  },
          {
    numb: 28,
    question: "What is the name of the wire joint as shown in the figure?",
    immg:"img28",
    answer: "Knotted tap joint",
    options: [
      "Aerial tap joint",
      "Knotted tap joint",
      "Duplex cross tap joint",
     "Double cross tap joint"
    ]
  },

      {
    numb: 29,
    question: "What is the full form of XLPE Cable?",
    
    answer: "Cross Linked Poly Ethylene",
    options: [
      "Cross Line Poly Ethylene",
      "X ess Line Phase Earthing",
      "Cross Linked Poly Ethylene",
     "Excess Length Paper and Ebonite"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 30,
    question: "How many electrons are there in the valence shell of a copper atom?",
    
    answer: "1",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "8",
     "18"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 31,
    question: "Which effect of the electric current takes place in the neon lamp?",
    
    answer: "Gas ionization effect",
    options: [
      "Heating effect",
      "Magnetic effect",
      "Chemical effect",
     "Gas ionization effect"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 32,
    question: "What is the unit of insulation resistance?",
    
    answer: "Mega ohm",
    options: [
      "Ohm",
      "Kilo ohm",
      "Milli Ohm",
     "Mega ohm"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 33,
    question: "Which type of soldering flux is used for soldering aluminium conductors?",
    
    answer: "Kynal flux",
    options: [
      "Tallow",
      "Kynal flux",
      "Zinc Chloride",
     "Sal ammonia"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 34,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked X in UG cables as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Lead sheath",
    immg:"img34",
    options: [
      "Serving",
      "Bedding",
      "Armouring",
     "Lead sheath"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 35,
    question: "What is the name of the joint as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Married joint",
    immg:"img35",
    options: [
      "Married joint",
      "Scarfed Joint",
      "Western Union Joint",
     "Britannia Sraight Joint"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 36,
    question: "What is the use of Britannia T joint?",
    
    answer: "Tapping the service connection from overhead lines",
    
    options: [
      "Extending the length of the lines",
      "Inside and outside wiring installation",
      "Mechanical stress not required on conductor",
     "Tapping the service connection from overhead lines"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 37,
    question: "What is the name of the part marked X of the belted U.G cable as shown in the figure?",
    
    answer: "Lead sheath",
    immg:"img37",
    options: [
      "Jute filling",
      "Armouring",
      "Lead sheath",
     "Paper insulation"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 38,
    question: "What is the purpose of the bedding insulation in the U.G. cable?",
    
    answer: "Protect the metallic sheath against corrosion",
 
    options: [
      "Protect the cable fromn mechanical injury",
      "Protect the cable from moisture and gases",
      "Protect armouring from atomspheric condition",
     "Protect the metallic sheath against corrosion"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 39,
    question: "What are the two classifications of system of units?",
    
    answer: "Fundamental and derived",
 
    options: [
      "British and Metric",
      "Gravitational and non gravitational",
      "Fundamental and derived",
     "Metric and International"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 40,
    question: "What are fundamental units?",
    
    answer: "Length, Mass, Time",
 
    options: [
      "Length, Mass, Volume",
      "Length, Mass, Time",
      "Length, Mass, Area",
     "Length, Pressure, Volume"
    ]
  },
       {
    numb: 41,
    question: "What denotes letter ' in MKS system?",
    
    answer: "Meter",
 
    options: [
      "Mile",
      "Milli Meter",
      "Meter",
     "Micron"
    ]
  },

       {
    numb: 42,
    question: "How many millimetres are there in 1 inch?",
    
    answer: "25.4mm",
 
    options: [
      "2.54mm",
      "25.4mm",
      "24.5mm",
     "2.45mm"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 43,
    question: "Convert decimal 0.000659 to fraction?",
    
    answer: "659/1000000",
 
    options: [
      "659/10000",
      "659/100000",
      "659/1000000",
     "659/1000"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 44,
    question: "What is the square root of 529?",
    
    answer: "23",
 
    options: [
      "13",
      "23",
      "33",
     "43"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 45,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
    immg:"img45",
    answer: "Water",
 
    options: [
      "Water",
      "Concrete",
      "Asbestos",
     "Glass"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 46,
    question: "Identify the conventional symbol of material?",
    immg:"img46",
    answer: "Wood",
 
    options: [
      "Lead",
      "Glass",
      "Wood",
     "Paper"
    ]
  },
     {
    numb: 47,
    question: "Identify the name of instrument?",
    immg:"img47",
    answer: "Protractor",
 
    options: [
      "Set Square",
      "Protractor",
      "French curve",
     "T Square"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 48,
    question: "Identify the name of set square?",
    immg:"img48",
    answer: "45o set square",
 
    options: [
      "15o Set Square",
      "60o set square",
      "30o set square",
     "45o set square"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 49,
    question: "Compass used to draw for___.",
    
    answer: "circle",
 
    options: [
      "rectangle",
      "square",
      "circle",
     "triangle"
    ]
  },
      {
    numb: 50,
    question: "a+b = 15, a-b=10 Then 4ab=? ",
    
    answer: "125",
 
    options: [
      "125",
      "100",
      "120",
     "135"
    ]
  },
  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];
